this is one of the coolest things I've
ever seen for two non-negative numbers
their arithmetic mean or simple average
is always greater than or equal to their
geometric mean or square root of their
product equality holds exactly when the
two numbers are equal there's an amazing
way to see this visually construct a
circle with diameter X Plus y the radius
of the circle is half the diameter so it
is the arithmetic mean now construct a
perpendicular chord where X meets y if
each semicard has length G then by the
chord chord power theorem G times G is
equal to x times Y which means G is
equal to the square root of x times y or
the geometric mean we can now
geometrically see the semi chord is
always less than or equal to the radius
with the quality if and only if x equals
y and that is precisely why the GM is
always less than or equal to the am and
thus we have proven the amgm inequality